Kelly Williams

kellymarjorie.github.io

kellymarjoriewilliams@gmail.com 0272 466 642

I am an energetic and enthusiastic designer, using my Bachelor of Fine Arts with my unique background working around the world to create beautiful web designs. With experience working in IT, I have the research and management skills to see projects through from beginning to end, and having recently returned from three years living and working in Japan, am seeking a challenging and rewarding position in Web Design to further my career.

Skills	Languages	Tools
Sketching	HTML	Sketch App
Usability testing	CSS3	Adobe Ps
User research	- Sass	Adobe Ai
Wireframes	- Bootstrap	Principle
Prototypes	Javascript	Visual Studio
User centric design	- jQuery	Git & Github
Visual communication		Trello
		Slack

Strengths

- Excellent written and verbal communication; comfortable with presenting, interviewing and documentating technical procedures.
- Strong problem solving skills, with a persistent and creative approach to finding solutions for new and unusual issues.
- Quick at understanding and mastering new technologies and programs, being extremely motivated to continually improve my knowledge and skillset.
- Extensive experience in client facing roles either in person, over the phone, or by email, and including researching technical needs and handling complaints.
- Strong familiarity with both Windows and OSX operating systems.
- Experience working in both lean and agile environments, and with DevOps practices.

Education

Whitecliffe College of Arts and Design Bachelor of Fine Arts 2006 - 2009

Projects

Portfolio Page - HTML5, CSS3 with Sass and Bootstrap

http://kellymarjorie.github.io

Creating and maintaining web responsive portfolio page to showcase visual UI work.

Random Quote Generator - HTML5, CSS3 with Bootstrap

End user is able to pull a quote randomly from array by pressing a button, and then tweet any quote using the Twitter plug-in.

Weather App - HTML5, CSS3 with Bootstrap, jQuery, API

Automatically pulls user location to show current weather information, including wind speeds, humidity, cloudiness, and allows user to toggle between celcius and fahrenheit

TwitchTV Channels - HTML5, CSS3 with Bootstrap, jQuery, API

Lists TwitchTV accounts the "user" follows, shows online/offline status, viewer count, and allows the end user to search for other channels.

Wikipedia Search - HTML5, CSS3 with Bootstrap, jQuery, API

End user can search using keywords for any relevant wikipedia article, and also request a random wikipedia page.

Professional Experience

09/2014 - **Abroad International School** - Nagoya, Japan 03/2017 *Preschool ESL Teacher*

- Increased my class size from four in my first year to 18 with a wait list in my final year, through creating a positive learning experience based on the visual impact of design elements in the classroom.
- Recognised the importance of a great relationship with parents identifying expectations, what they
 each defined as success, and maintaining consistent communication. One of the outcomes from this
 investigation was that I created an end of year review portfolio for each child with a heavy visual
 element; this was received so well it has been adopted by the school for all classrooms.
- Assisted the school management in their exchanges in English to parents when neither party were native speakers, by drafting and proofreading digital and printed correspondence.

- Asisted in the roll-out of CRM (Salesforce) system; I was responsible for user training and part of the team for system administration and data management, including data entry.
- Managed in-house training workshops; I interviewed employees to find out their training requirements and then planned and delivered workshops to cater to those needs.
- Worked with Project Managers and Business Analysts to procide technical support and working systems to meet their needs but still within the strict government guidelines.
- Provided administration based assistance to the EDRMS project team, which included monitoring use of

the system, assigning user permissions, and delivering new employee training.

• Supported the development of internal user guides to uplift in-house self-service capabilities.

08/2011 - **Amey PLC** - Oxford, United Kingdom 02/2013 *Senior IT Analyst*

- Part of the team that delivered national company workshops to unit and understand the different demands and processes of each division. This involved arranging outside professionals to provide onsite education presentations or holding Q&A seminars, as well as creating an employee platform (Sharepoint) for best practices to be shared.
- Supervised a second tier support Mobile IT helpdesk, and consistently met and raised SLA targets, surpassing previous benchmarks.
- Took ownership of the project to create and maintain process documentation, versed with the Lean method, to ensure a consistent approach for communication and issue resolution for the helpdesk team, end users, and for an external first-tier helpdesk.
- Instrumental in raising a position image of IT within the company with excellent customer service, measured by internal surveys. Nominated three times for a company customer service awards program, winning once.
- Primary liaison with company mobile service provider and multiple external mobile IT companies.
- Sole management of the company's mobile connection contract, averaging at £150,000 a month. This
 included asset management, monitoring costs on 8500+ connections, decision making on new contracts
 and procurement options, and analysing billing data and reporting back on this to different levels of
 management.
- Oversaw the end to end process of implementing an online mobile device billing software for over 8000 end users.
- Assisted in the mobile device appropriation for new and existing government and public service contracts.

04/2011 -Prego Cocktail Bar - Darlington, United Kingdom 07/2011 Bartender Telecom (Spark) - Christchurch, New Zealand 08/2010 -02/2011 Communication Consultant 02/2010 -Madras Cafe Bookshop - Christchurch, New Zealand 08/2010 Cafe Manager NOOD - Christchurch, New Zealand 12/2008 -02/2010 Barista, Retail Assistant

References

References available upon request.